

ROUNAK NAYEE



Summary

Graduate Student in Computer Science with 2 years of professional experience in the cloud software industry with strong foundations in Networks, Algorithms, Mathematics, programming, and Databases, seeking full-time opportunities in the Technology domain to enhance my abilities and contribute to my organization.

Education

Rutgers University

September 2022 – December 2023

Master of Science in Computer Science

New Jersey, USA

Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Distributed parallel and cloud computing, Mobile Development.

- Teaching Assitant for Operating Systems and C & Unix and Chancellor Meritorious Scholarship recipient.

KJ Somaiya College Of Engineering

August 2016 - October 2020

Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering

Mumbai, India

Relevant Coursework : Cloud Computing, Data structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems and RTOS, OOP, Cryptography, Big Data, Image Processing, Computer Networks.

Experience

New Jersey Transit

June 2023 – present

Cloud Software Engineer Intern

Newark, New Jersey

- Implemented AWS infrastructure using Terraform, services such as AWS Transcribe, AWS Managed Active Directory, and VMware with vSphere to enhance the scalability and cost-efficiency of the NJT Application.
- Developed PS Scripts and AWS Lambda Functions to automate tasks reducing manual time required by 50%.
- Partnered with the project manager to diligently manage project portfolios through the effective utilization of project management software, such as monday.com, while ensuring regular reporting and communication with senior leadership.

Wolters Kluwer

October 2020 - July 2022

Infrastructure Technology Analyst

Mumbai, India

- Responsible for designing, maintaining, and configuring virtual machines, databases, virtual networks, and serverless functions on cloud platforms MS Azure and Amazon Web Services (AWS).
- Collaborated with a team of 4 people on the project for journey to cloud, re-architecting the existing infrastructure from physical data centers to cloud, reducing the overall expenditure by 55%.
- Integrated 150+ subscriptions in AWS and Azure into Opsramp, Rapid7 and ServiceNow systems for an efficient single point of management with interactive data dashboards and critical metrics.
- Managed and implemented Barracuda WAF along with AWS CloudFront and Route 53 for DNS Management.

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

September 2023

Software Engineering on Forage Platform

New Jersey, USA

• Designed a web server application in Java Spring Boot with REST APIs that can accept and respond to HTTP requests as well as support uploading JSON data and developed unit tests with Mockito to test APIs.

Projects

Speakeasy | Terraform, AWS Transcribe, AWS Lambda, Python, CloudFlare, Twilio

Designed a Whatsapp Bot to Convert Speech to Text and Image to Text directly through chat integrating Meta API.

Tech Impact - Volunteer connect | React JS, Express, Redis, MySQL, Docker

Developed web application utilizing the React JS, Express JS (Node Framework), and utilizing Redis and MySQL for data storage with JWT Authentication along with docker for CI/CD deployment.

Web Portal for Career cell of university | Python, Spacy, Azure, Django, HTML, CSS

Trained NLP models using python SpaCy to extract the unstructured data from different types and formats of documents and Implemented a Web-based portal using the Django MVC Framework.

Technical Skills

Languages: C, C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

Technologies/Frameworks: Django, Flask, GIT, VSCode, Azure, AWS, Windows, Linux, MySQL, React, Ansible, NoSQL (MongoDB), Jenkins, Docker containers, Kubernetes, Node.js, Terraform.

Certifications: Azure Cloud Architect (AZ-104), Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900), C++ on Udemy.